Finding Aid for James K. Pollock Papers, 1920-1968
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Governmental Public Service 1948-1968, 18 linear feet
  - Hoover Commission 1948-1949
    - Citizens for the Hoover Report
      - 1949-1951 (Box 44)
        [44-9a]
      - 1949-1952 (Box 44)
        [44-10a]
      - 1950 (Box 44)
      - 1950-1952, 3 folders (Box 44)
        [44-1a; 44-4a; 44-5a]
      - 1952 (Box 44)
        [44-2a]
      - May 1950-September 1951 (Box 44)
        [44-6a]
      - October 1, 1951-February 18, 1952 (Box 44)
        [44-7a]
      - February 21, 1952-July 6, 1952 (Box 44)
        [44-8a]
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 44)
        [44-11a; 44-19]
      - 1950 (Box 44)
        (include speeches by Marx Leva, Asst. Sec. of Defense)
        [44-12]
      - Speeches before U.S. Congress 1949-1952 (Box 44)
        [44-13]
      - Speeches before U.S. Congress 1952, 2 folders (Box 44)
        [44-14; 44-15]
      - James K. Pollock speeches and speech material (Box 44)
        [44-16]
      - James K. Pollock speeches and materials on Overseas Administration (Box 44)
        [44-17]
      - Proposed bills relating to Hoover Report 1951 (Box 44)
        [44-18]
    - State and Local Chairmen correspondence
      - 1950-1952 (Box 44)
        [44-1b]
      - 1952 (Box 44)
        [44-2b]
    - Circular letters 1950 (Box 44)
      [44-3b]
    - Washington Watch Dogs (incomplete) 1950-1952 (Box 44)
      [44-5b]
    - News releases
      - May 1950-September 1951 (Box 44)
        [44-6b]
      - October 1, 1951-February 18, 1952 (Box 44)
        [44-7b]
      - February 21, 1952-July 6, 1952 (Box 44)
        [44-8b]
    - Speakers Bureau material (Box 44)
      [44-9b]
    - Publications (Reorganization News, Committee Reporter) (Box 44)
      [44-10b]
    - Progress reports (Box 44)
      [44-11b]
    - Miscellanea 1948-1952 (Box 44)
      [44-20]
    - Clippings re Hoover Report (Box 44)
      [44-21]
  - Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations
    - 1959-1961
      - Agendas 1960-1961 (Box 45)
        [45-1a]
      - Appointments (staff) 1959-1962 (Box 45)
        [45-1b]
      - Bane, Frank. Correspondence 1959-1962, 1966 (Box 45)
        [45-3]
      - Briefing papers 1959-1961 (Box 45)
        [45-4]
      - Census Advisory Committee
        - General (Box 45)
          [45-19]
        - 1960 (Box 45)
          [45-20]
      - Colman, William G. Correspondence 1960-1961, 2 folders (Box 45)
        [45-5; 45-6]
      - Commissioners material (Box 45)
        [45-7a]
      - Correspondence (General) 1959-1961 (Box 45)
        [45-7b]
      - Department of Urban Affairs subcommittee 1961 (Box 45)
        [45-2]
      - Docket books
        - May 25, 1960 (Box 45)
          [45-12]
        - December 9-10, 1960 (Box 45)
          [45-11]
        - April 27-28, 1961 (Box 45)
          [45-10]
        - June 15-16, 1961 (Box 45)
          [45-9a]
        - September 14-15, 1961 (Box 45)
          [45-9b]
        - November 30-December 1, 1961 (Box 45)
          [45-8]
      - Manvel, Allen D. Correspondence 1961 (Box 45)
        [45-15a]
      - Minutes of Meetings 1959-1961 (Box 45)
        [45-13]
      - Miscellaneous 1959-1961 (Box 45)
        [45-14]
      - Newsletter 1960-1961 (Box 45)
        [45-15b]
      - North Carolina Seminar December 1960 (Box 45)
        [45-16a]
      - Personnel Records 1959 (Box 45)
        [45-16b]
      - Port of New York Authority case 1960 (Box 45)
        [45-16c]
      - Report of January 31, 1960 (Box 45)
        [45-17a]
      - Speech materials (James K. Pollock) (Box 45)
        [45-17b]
      - Speeches (James K. Pollock) (Box 45)
        [45-18]
      - Travel vouchers and statements (James K. Pollock) (Box 45)
        [45-17c]
      - Draft Reports
        - Investment of Idle Cash Balances by Local Units of Government 1960 (Box 46)
          [46-1]
        - Modification of Federal Grants-in-Aid for Public Health Services 1960 (Box 46)
          [46-2]
        - Periodic Congressional Reassessment of Federal Grants-in-Aid to State and Local Governments 1960 (Box 46)
          [46-3]
        - State Constitutional and Statutory Restrictions on Local Government Debt 1960 (Box 46)
          [46-5]
        - Intergovernmental Responsibilities with Respect to Mass Transportation Facilities and Services in Metropolitan Areas 1961 (Box 46)
          [46-7]
        - Governmental Structure, Organization and Planning in Metropolitan Areas 1961 (Box 46)
          [46-8]
        - Coordination of State and Federal Inheritance, Estate and Gift Taxes 1960 (Box 46)
          [46-9]
        - Periodic Congressional Reassessment of Federal Grants-in Aid to State and Local Governments 1960 (Box 46)
          [46-10]
        - Periodic Congressional Reassessment of Federal Grants-in-Aid to State and Local Governments 1961 (Box 46)
          [46-11]
        - Modification of Federal Grants-in-Aid for Public Health Services 1960 (Box 46)
          [46-12]
        - Investment of Idle Cash Balances by State and Local Government 1960 (Box 46)
          [46-13]
    - 1962-1968
      - Correspondence with William G. Colman 1962-1968 (Box 46)
        [46-14]
      - Circular Correspondence
        - October 1962-July 1963 (Box 46)
          [46-15]
        - October 1963-December 1963 (Box 46)
          [46-16]
        - January 1964-September 1964 (Box 46)
          [46-17]
        - October 1964, December 1964 (Box 46)
          [46-18]
        - January 1965-March 1965 (Box 47)
          [47-1]
        - April 1965-August 1965 (Box 47)
          [47-2]
        - September 1965-December 1965 (Box 47)
          [47-3]
        - January 1966-February 1966 (Box 47)
          [47-4]
        - March 1966-April 1966 (Box 47)
          [47-5]
        - May 1966-June 1966 (Box 47)
          [47-6]
        - July 1966-September 1966 (Box 47)
          [47-7]
        - October 1966 (Box 47)
          [47-8]
        - November 1966-December 1966 (Box 47)
          [47-9]
        - January 1967-May 1967 (Box 47)
          [47-10]
        - June 1967-September 1967 (Box 47)
          [47-11]
        - October 1967 (Box 47)
          [47-12]
        - November 1967-December 1967 (Box 47)
          [47-13]
        - January 1968-April 1968 (Box 47)
          [47-14]
        - May 1968-June 1968 (Box 47)
          [47-15]
        - July 1968 (Box 47)
          [47-16]
        - August 1968-October 1968 (Box 47)
          [47-17]
      - News releases and speeches of Sen. Edmund Muskie 1962-1966 (Box 47)
        [47-18]
      - Reports 1966-1968 (Box 47)
        [47-19]
      - Bibliographies and accession lists 1963-1968 (Box 47)
        [47-20]
      - Miscellanea (Box 47)
        [47-21]
      - Docket Book September 20, 1968 (Box 48)
        [48-1]
      - Draft report: Intergovernmental Problems in Medicaid 1968 (Box 48)
        [48-2]
      - Miscellaneous speeches and statements, 2 folders (Box 48)
        [48-3; 48-4]
  - Michigan Constitutional Convention
    The subseries of Constitutional Convention papers include official reports, research papers and accounts of the deliberations. There are also extensive clipping files, correspondence and material relating to the selling of the constitution to the citizenry of Michigan.
    - Topical Files
      - AFL-CIO material (Box 48)
        [48-6]
      - AFL-CIO material; Michigan AFL-CIO News 1961-1962 (Box 48)
        [48-7]
      - Appointment material (Box 48)
        [48-8]
      - Chamber of Commerce material (Box 48)
        [48-9a]
      - Civil Service material (Box 48)
        [48-9b]
      - Committee for a Sound Constitution (Box 48)
        [48-10a]
      - Conservation material (Box 48)
        [48-10b]
      - Declaration of Rights materials, 4 folders (Box 48)
        [48-11; 48-12; 48-13; 48-14]
      - Delegates directories (Box 48)
        [48-15a]
      - Delegates Column December 21, 1961-May 2, 1962 (Box 48)
        [48-15b]
      - Education material (Box 48)
        [48-16]
      - Elections material (Box 48)
        [48-17]
      - Emerging Problems Committee (Box 48)
        [48-18]
      - Executive Branch Committee, 2 folders (Box 48)
        [48-19; 48-20]
      - Executive Branch Committee, 4 folders (Box 49)
        [49-1; 49-2; 49-3; 49-4]
      - Fiscal Interests material (Box 49)
        [49-5a]
      - Gambling and Entertainment material (Box 49)
        [49-5b]
      - Government (miscellaneous) (Box 49)
        [49-6a]
      - Highways and Automobiles material (Box 49)
        [49-6b]
      - Internal Convention Elections and Preparation data (Box 49)
        [49-6c]
      - Judicial Branch Committee (Box 49)
        [49-7a]
      - Judicial Interests material (Box 49)
        [49-7b]
      - Justice of the Peace material (Box 49)
        [49-8a]
      - League of Women Voters (Box 49)
        [49-8b]
      - Legislative Organization Committee, 7 folders (Box 49)
        [49-9 to 49-15]
      - Library Associations material (Box 49)
        [49-16a]
      - Local Government material, 2 folders (Box 49)
        [49-16b; 49-18]
      - Mental Health, Social Welfare, Physical Disability material (Box 49)
        [49-16c]
      - Michigan Council of College Presidents (Box 49)
        [49-17]
      - Michigan Education Association material (Box 49)
        [49-19b]
      - Michigan Farm Bureau material (Box 49)
        [49-19a]
      - Michigan Manufacturers Association material (Box 49)
        [49-20]
      - Michigan Township Officials material (Box 50)
        [50-1a]
      - Natural Gas material (Box 50)
        [50-1b]
      - Political Party material (Box 50)
        [50-2]
      - Property Taxation material (Box 50)
        [50-1c]
      - Public Officers and Employment material, 3 folders (Box 50)
        [50-3; 50-4; 50-5]
      - Rights, Suffrage and Election Interests material (Box 50)
        [50-6]
      - Religious Interests material (Box 50)
        [50-7a]
    - Working/Research Files
      - Amendments (miscellaneous) (Box 50)
        [50-7c]
      - Michigan Con-Con Studies 1961, 3 folders (Box 50)
        [50-8; 50-9; 50-10]
      - Citizens Advisory Committee Report 1961 (Box 50)
        [50-11]
      - Background of the convention (Box 50)
        [50-12]
      - Composition of the convention (Box 50)
        [50-13]
      - Committees, material on (Box 50)
        [50-14a]
      - Analysis of Convention Action (Box 50)
        [50-14b]
      - Pollock campaign and election materials (Box 50)
        [50-15]
      - Style and Drafting, rules and procedural data (Box 50)
        [50-16]
      - Calendars and work schedules, 2 folders (Box 50)
        [50-17; 50-18]
      - "Third Reading" (Box 50)
        [50-19]
      - Weekly Con-Con Reviews (Box 50)
        [50-20]
      - Weekly Delegates' Report (Box 50)
        [50-21]
      - Clippings (miscellaneous) (Box 50)
        [50-22]
      - Clippings-Ann Arbor News (Box 51)
        [51-1]
      - Clippings-James K. Pollock (Box 51)
        [51-2]
      - James K. Pollock Saturday Morning Seminars 1961-1962, 3 folders (Box 51)
        [51-3; 51-4; 51-5]
      - Correspondence May 1961-December 1961 (Box 51)
        [51-6]
      - Correspondence January 1962-March 1962 (Box 51)
        [51-7]
      - Correspondence April 1962-May 1962 (Box 51)
        [51-8]
      - Miscellanea (Box 51)
        [51-9]
      - James K. Pollock speeches and remarks (Box 51)
        [51-10]
      - James K. Pollock Convention diary (Box 51)
        [51-12]
      - Action Journal
        - Committee on Legislative Organization (Box 51)
          [51-13]
        - Committee on Declaration of Rights, Suffrage and Elections (Box 51)
          [51-14]
        - Committee on Executive Branch (Box 51)
          [51-16]
      - Miscellanea 1962 (Box 51)
        [51-15]
      - Bibliographies (Box 51)
        [51-17]
      - Research folder no. 1. U.S. Supreme Court Case: Baker v Carr 1962 (Box 51)
        [51-18]
      - Research folders nos. 2-3, 3 folders (Box 51)
        [51-19; 51-20; 51-21]
      - Research folder no. 4 (Box 52)
        [52-1]
      - Citizens Research Council of Michigan (Box 52)
        [52-2]
      - Press releases, 2 folders (Box 52)
        [52-2; 52-3]
      - Citizens Research Council Analysis of Proposed Constitution (Box 52)
        [52-5]
      - Michigan Supreme Court case: Scholle v Hare and Beadle (Box 52)
        [52-6]
      - Correspondence re James K. Pollock's paper "Making Michigan's New Constitution" 1963 (Box 52)
        [52-7]
      - Late papers 1962-1963 (Box 52)
        [52-8]
      - Press releases concerning passage of new constitution (Box 52)
        [52-10]
      - Papers concerning passage of new constitution (Box 52)
        [52-11]
      - Miscellanea, 3 folders (Box 52)
        [52-12; 52-13; 52-20]
      - James K. Pollock speeches and outlines, 3 folders (Box 52)
        [52-14; 52-15; 52-16]
      - Excerpts from the Con-Con Record (Box 52)
        [52-17]
      - Con-Con Research papers 1, 5, 7 (Box 52)
        [52-18]
      - James K. Pollock paper: "Making Michigan's New Constitution" (Box 52)
        [52-19]
      - Citizens Research Council reports on the proposed constitution June 1962, August 1962 (Box 53)
        [53-1]
      - Miscellaneous papers, 2 folders (Box 53)
  - Citizens Conference on State Legislatures
    - Correspondence
      - 1965 (Box 53)
        [53-8]
      - January 1966-June 1966 (Box 53)
        [53-7]
      - July 1966-December 1966 (Box 53)
        [53-6]
      - 1967 (Box 53)
        [53-5]
      - 1968 (Box 53)
    - Newsletters 1966-1968 (Box 53)
      [53-9]
    - Information bulletins 1967-1968 (Box 53)
      [53-10]
    - Research memoranda 1967-1968 (Box 53)
      [53-11]
    - Trustees handbook 1965 (Box 53)
      [53-12]
    - Organizational, financial and personnel data 1965-1967 (Box 53)
      [53-13]
    - Information on meetings 1966 (Box 53)
      [53-14]
    - Handbook on Trustees meeting 1967 (Box 53)
      [53-15]
    - Meeting of November 30, 1966 (Box 53)
      [53-16]
    - Meeting of September 7-8, 1967 (Box 53)
      [53-17]
    - Meeting of February 14-15, 1968 (Box 53)
      [53-18]
    - Meeting of May 22-23, 1968 (Box 53)
      [53-19]
    - Proposal to Kellogg Foundation August 9, 1968 (Box 53)
      [53-20]
    - Research reports, 3 folders (Box 54)
      [54-1; 54-2; 54-3]
    - Selected Bibliography on State Legislatures June 1968 (Box 54)
      [54-4]
    - American Assembly conference: "State Legislatures in American Politics 1966 (Box 54)
      [54-5]
    - Miscellaneous speeches and articles on state government 1965-1967 (Box 54)
      [54-6; 54-7]
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets and brochures on state government (Box 54)
      [54-8]
    - American Assembly, Colorado meeting December 1-4, 1966 (Box 54)
      [54-12]
    - Conference on Comparative Research in State Politics August 1966, 2 folders (Box 54)
      [54-13; 54-14]
  - Governor's Special Commission on Legislative Compensation
    - 1965-1966, 3 folders (Box 54)
      [54-18; 54-19; 54-20]
    - Report on Legislative Compensation in Colorado and Indiana 1965 (Box 55)
      [55-1]
    - Report of Legislative Service Bureau (2 volumes0 (Box 55)
      [55-2; 55-3]
    - Report-1st draft 1966 (Box 55)
      [55-4]
    - Report-2nd draft 1966 (Box 55)
      [55-5]
    - Final report and excerpts 1966 (Box 55)
      [55-6]
  - Congressional organization, reapportionment, other issues
    - Joint Committee on the Organization of Congress 1965 (Box 55)
      [55-11]
    - Legislative reapportionment (national), 4 folders (Box 55)
      [55-12; 55-13; 55-14; 55-15]
    - Legislative reapportionment (states)
      - General (Box 55)
        [55-16]
      - Ohio (Box 55)
        [55-17]
      - Michigan 1964-1965, 3 folders (Box 55)
        [55-18; 55-19; 55-20]
    - Campaign Finance
      - James K. Pollock article: "Problems of Campaign Finance" 1967, 2 folders (Box 55)
        (drafts and research material)
        [55-21; 55-22]
- Germany: Research and Official Responsibilities, 1935-1967, 16 linear feet
  Grouped together under Germany: Research and Official Responsibilities (1935-1967; 16 linear ft.) are Pollock's files beginning with his first interest in Germany when he was an American observer to the Saar plebiscite in 1935 and continuing with his post-World War II responsibilities with the Office of the Military Government (U.S.), his studies of German elections in the 1950s and 1960s, and his participation in the Franz Lieber Foundation.
  - Saar: American observer to the Saar plebiscite, 1935
    - Analyses
      - Victor Bruns Die volksabstimmung im Saargebiet (1934) (Box 56)
        [56-1]
      - Adolf Grabowsky and G.W. Sante Die grundlagen des Saarkampfes (1934) (Box 56)
        [56-2]
      - Frank M. Russell The international government of the Saar (1926) (Box 56)
        [56-3]
      - Royal Institute of International Affairs, Information Papers, no. 11 and 14 The Saar plebiscite (1934) (Box 56)
        [56-4]
      - Miscellaneous analyses (Box 56)
        [56-5]
    - Administration
      - Volksabstimmungskommission des Volkerbundes, "Auszug aus der liste der stimmberechtigten, die am 28.6.1919 in der gemeinde Saarbruckern Einwohnereigenschaft besassen, im Wahlburo Nr. 13 (Box 56)
        [56-6]
      - Miscellaneous 1934-1935 (Box 56)
        [56-7]
    - Clippings 1934-1935 (Box 56)
      [56-8]
    - Correspondence 1934-1935 (Box 56)
      [56-9]
    - Saar plebiscite 1934-1935 (Box 56)
      [56-10]
    - Regulations for plebiscite (Box 56)
      [56-11]
  - Saar Study 1955
    - Analyses
      - Student paper: Shirley Davis The Saar problem, undated (Box 56)
        [56-12]
      - Pamphlets and reports (Box 56)
        [56-13]
    - Legal provisions
      - Gesetzgebund und Abkommend des Saarlandes (1954) (Box 56)
        [56-14a]
      - Laws 1955-1956, 2 folders (Box 56)
        [56-14b; 56-15]
      - International agreements 1955-1956, 2 folders (Box 56)
        [56-16; 56-17]
    - Publications 1952-1955 (Box 58)
      [58-1]
    - Statistical material 1952-1955 (Box 58)
      [58-2]
    - Clippings 1955-1957 (Box 58)
      [58-3]
  - Office of the Military Government for Germany (U.S.) 1945-1946 and later official observatory and fact-finding missions to Germany, 1947, 1948, 1950
    The largest subseries under the Germany series relates to Pollock's responsibility with Office of the Military Government (U.S.) in the period of 1945-1946 and his role as official observer and member of fact-finding missions to Germany in 1947, 1948, and 1950. As a scholar as well as a participant, Pollock was careful in recording his observations and activities. He maintained a valuable diary for the period of 1945-1946 and 1948 and was diligent in preserving the documentation that crossed his desk - reports, memoranda, meeting materials, and speeches. The importance of the diary was readily recognized by German scholars. In 1994, Ingrid Krüger-Bulcke published Besatzune und Staatsaufbau nach 1945 which is a transcript of Pollock's "Occupation Diary" and his private correspondence with his wife and some of his colleagues in the period of 1945 to 1948. A positive microfilm of this diary is also available. The library also has a negative microfilm for the entire subseries originally created for a researcher.
    The subseries also contains much material on the proceedings of the Länderrat, including protocols of all of its meetings through 1948. There is also material on organization, proposals, the results of actions taken, and relations with the Regional Government Coordinating Office. Other files pertain to the United States zonal government as a whole and its relations with the other zones. There are further files on the economic situation in Germany, the progress of denazification, and reports on the conferences of the Council of Foreign Ministers. Extensive files of correspondence from this period is available with General Lucius Clay, Robert Murphy, and John McCloy. (A microfilm negative of this entire series was produced fora researcher. Consult reference staff concerning access)
    - Travel orders, memoranda, etc
      - 1945-1946, 2 folders (Box 58)
        [58-4; 58-5]
      - 1947 (Box 58)
        [58-6]
      - 1948 (Box 58)
        [58-7]
      - 1950 (Box 58)
        [58-8]
    - Reports/observations
      - Reports to High Commissioner 1950 (Box 58)
        [58-9]
      - Reports, field notes, orders, correspondence 1950 (Box 58)
        [58-10]
      - Occupation diary
        - July 1945-April 1946 (Box 58)
          (original, typescript, etc.)
          [58-11]
        - April-Aug 1946 (Box 58)
          [58-12]
        - May-June 1948 (Box 58)
          [58-13]
    - Regional Government Coordinating Office
      - Summary Reports on Meetings of the Länderrat Directorate
        - Nos. 1-20 June 21, 1946-January 7, 1947 (Box 58)
          [58-14]
        - Nos. 21-30 January 16, 1947-April 24, 1947 (Box 58)
          [58-15]
        - Nos. 31-40 May 5, 1947-August 28, 1947 (Box 59)
          [59-1]
        - Nos. 41-50 September 4, 1947-December 30, 1947 (Box 59)
          [59-2]
        - Nos. 51-60 January 13, 1948-May 21, 1948 (Box 59)
          [59-3]
      - Land governments, minister-präsidents (U.S. Zone) 1945 (Box 59)
        [59-4]
      - Memoranda from OMGUS 1945-1946 (Box 59)
        [59-4b]
      - Liaison Officer's Meetings 1947 (Box 59)
        [59-4c]
    - Länderrat
      - Establishment and formative stage October 1945-December 1945 (Box 59)
        [59-5]
      - Secretary General, biographical sketch and structure 1945 (Box 59)
        [59-6]
      - Organization-Statutes and charts 1945-1948 (Box 59)
        [59-7]
      - Directorate-Statutes, constitutional meeting and related (Box 59)
        [59-8]
      - Reorganization-Establishment of Parliamentary Advisory Council 1947 (Box 59)
        [59-9]
      - Lists of meetings, composition, activity 1945-1947 (Box 59)
        [59-10]
      - Agenda of meetings January 8, 1946-March 11, 1947 (Box 59)
        [59-11]
      - Legislation 1946-1949 (Box 59)
        [59-12]
      - Meetings
        - Decisions and results 1946 (Box 59)
          [59-13]
        - Summary reports
          - Nos. 8-16 May 7, 1946-January 8, 1947 (Box 59)
            [59-14]
          - Nos. 17-24 February 4, 1947-September 9, 1947 (Box 59)
            [59-15]
          - Nos. 25-31 October 7, 1947-April 8, 1948 (Box 59)
            [59-16]
          - Nos. 33-34 (German version) 1948 (Box 59)
            [59-19]
          - Nos. 35-36 (German version) 1949 (Box 59)
            [59-20]
      - Lists of proposed laws as of 1949, 2 folders (Box 59)
        [59-17; 59-18]
      - Requests to Military Government
        - From 5th Meeting February 5, 1946 (Box 59)
          [59-21]
        - From 6th Meeting March 5, 1946 (Box 59)
          [59-22]
        - From 7th Meeting April 2, 1946, 3 folders (Box 59)
          [59-23; 59-24; 59-25]
        - From 8-10 Meetings May 7, 1946-July 2, 1946 (Box 60)
          [60-1]
      - Press Material (Box 60)
        [60-2]
      - Memo of British Intelligence and note on reorganization of the Länder in the British Zone 1945-1946 (Box 60)
        [60-6]
      - Denazification law
        - Munich Conference March 5, 1946 (Box 60)
          [60-7]
        - Amendments 1946-1947 (Box 60)
          [60-8]
      - Monthly Reports of Military Governor 1945-1947 (Box 60)
        [60-13]
      - Report of Action taken by the Military Government on Länderrat recommendations 1946 (Box 60)
        [60-14]
      - Lucius Clay speeches 1945-1948 (Box 60)
        [60-15]
      - Lucius Clay press conferences 1946-1947 (Box 60)
        [60-16]
      - James K. Pollock speeches and reports 1945-1946 (Box 60)
        [60-17]